How're you feeling, Tomo?
Top of my game, obviously!
I've been through all the
training for this marathon!
Me, too.
I'm gonna win this one.
Oh, yeah? That's some big talk!
How about the loser has to pay
for a week's worth of drinks?
Sounds good! I hope you
don't regret that later!
The girls and boys aren't
even running the same route.
Just leave them be.
Hey, he's been trying to send us
some kind of signal this whole time.
Watch me, Misuzu-chan!
I'll finish this marathon for you!
Just leave him be.
Everyone, on your marks!
Great. They're all full of energy for...
At least run at the very beginning!
You heard her.
Oh, fine.
How the Contest Ends
"How the Contest Ends."
You haven't been enjoying karate
with me lately, have you?
No, that's not...
It's okay. I get it.
But today, you're putting all your
strength into keeping up with me.
Tomo...
But no matter how hard you run,
I'm gonna leave you behind in the end!
Don't cry, okay?
Bring it on! You're the
one who better not cry!
Marathons are a total drag.
I'm, like, so wiped!
Keep it up, everyone!
Hanao-chan's cheating!
Like, so not fair!
It's perfectly fair.
Wow, they've already made it this far?
Impressive!
I'm not letting...
...anyone...
...run in front of me!
Why, though?! Why?!
Why?!
This really is fun!
I still feel the best when
I'm competing with her!
Girls' Turning Point
Oh, yeah... I got so
excited, I didn't notice.
We weren't competing on equal
footing to begin with...
Huh?!
Hey, hang on, Tomo! You passed it!
You just passed it!
Huh? Passed what?
The girls' turning point!
Hah! That don't mean squat!
Huh?
You wanna compete with me, don't you?!
Yeah...
Yeah!
I'm impressed, Kosuke.
We're distance runners in the
track club, and look at you.
I'm feeling good today for some reason.
I've gotten stronger! It's clear now!
Those two made the turn already?
Damn, that's fast! Are they human?!
I've got a long way to go.
Damn it! I still can't catch up to Tomo?
Tomo?!
You're burning up!
How could you get knocked flat by a fever?
Did you do something weird yesterday?!
Yesterday? Yesterday...
I went out to run right
after I finished dinner...
and I think I got back around 10 PM.
How many hours did you run?!
After that... I took a bath and went to bed...
but when I woke up,
for some reason, I was naked.
I didn't do anything weird.
Like hell you didn't!
No wonder you have a fever!
Hey, Tomo!
Damn it!
What now? I don't have my phone,
and the teacher's with the
group a few kilometers back.
No sign of any cars coming, either.
What am I, dumb?!
What's there to even think about?!
I've got...
this body...
that I've been building up!
T-Tomo...
Keep calm and listen to me.
Y-You have a cold.
Okay. I think you need to calm down first.
I see. So Jun carried me back, huh?
That's what I heard.
I put him through a lot of trouble.
And we were looking forward
to this marathon...
But he finished first, apparently.
Huh?! But wasn't he carrying me?
That's probably why.
Tomo, should you be awake already?
Jun?!
I'll be going now.
You almost never get sick,
so take advantage of this.
Advantage?
Since you're always so strong,
showing weakness will be effective.
Depend on him for everything.
Would you wake up already?
Here's some water.
Oh... Thanks.
You and Misuzu are being nicer
to me than usual today.
It's throwing me off.
You wouldn't know since you've
never been badly hurt or sick,
but that's what happens when
you're too weak to even move.
That's how it is, huh?
Akemi-san's coming to pick you up.
Can you walk, Tomo?
Yeah...
Actually, no.
C-Carry me!
Huh?!
You carried me here on your back, right?
I don't remember any of it, so do it again!
That doesn't even make sense!
C-Carry me, damn it! I'm sick here!
You seem healthy to me.
Okay, fine.
Oh, so this is what it feels like.
You've gotten a lot bigger.
So have you...
Me? I've what?
Uh, sorry. Forget I said anything.
Sorry for everything that happened today.
I even ruined our contest.
Don't worry about it.
Whenever you're having trouble,
of course I'm gonna help you.
If you're having trouble with something,
Jun...
Tomo!
Her dad?!
Where is Tomo?!
In the car, heading for the hospital...
Wait for me, Tomo!
Green onions?
Hey, Jun! Thanks for coming!
I came to check in on you, but...
I guess I shouldn't be surprised.
I'm totally fine now!
But Mom refuses to let me go outside.
Obviously.
I forgot to say it with
everything going on, but...
I guess... Thanks for yesterday.
S-Sure... But don't be so reckle—
Oh, yeah!
Here. I'm returning this.
This...
How long can I borrow it?
Until I'm a stronger man than you.
When that time comes...
I'll take it back!
You said you'd take it back when you
were a stronger man than me, right?
You'd better not have it in your head
that you can beat me in everything now.
I won't lose to anyone on my own turf!
But that goes for both of us.
Right?
You have a problem being
on even footing with me?
Nah.
It's the best way to be.
To Stay Best Friends...
"To Stay Best Friends..."
Aizawa Dojo
Right before we started middle school,
I managed...
to land a hit on Tomo for the first time.
Ow...
I did it!
I landed a hit on you! On Tomo!
Huh... I guess you finally caught up to me.
It's kinda sad.
Sad? Not frustrating?
That happened sooner than I expected.
Huh?
Akemi's been going on
about it for a long time.
She always says Tomo's got natural talent,
that no matter what sport Tomo plays,
no one else will stand a chance.
But walking the path I walk,
the path where one can't
choose one's own opponent,
won't do our child any good.
What does that mean?
Entrance Ceremony
I finally get to go to
the same school as Tomo!
I bet he'll look awesome
in the school uniform!
Hey, Jun!
We can finally go to school together!
You're getting a little too
crazy with that skirt!
What kind of new start are you making?
Huh?!
Huh?
What? Junichiro thought you were a boy?
Yes, he did!
I knew he was an idiot,
but I had no idea it went that far.
So what are you going to do?
You can't just act the same around
him as you always have, can you?
Nah, I think it'll be fine!
Neither of us cares about stuff
like who's a boy or a girl!
I really don't think it'll be that simple.
Tomo's a girl.
Now that I think about it...
Who wouldn't have noticed?!
Did I just not want to notice?
I can't even laugh at this.
Hey,
Kubota-kun.
You seem to be pretty close
to Aizawa-san in Class C.
You going out?
Right... Of course people would think that!
I feel so awkward trying
to get Tomo's attention.
Hey, Aizawa-san, are you going out
with Kubota-kun from Class A?
No way!
Oh, you're not?
Really?
Yeah, he doesn't even see me as a girl.
And then this dude...
Don't talk about that!
So then what happened?
Hey, it's Jun!
Who?
Is he your friend?
Since we were kids.
Right, Jun?
Was that bloodlust emanating from him?
Scary...
What the heck am I doing?!
A whole year went by,
and I never apologized to Tomo.
We basically ended up on
the level of acquaintances
who only talked to each other
when it was necessary.
I really wanna just make
up with her already.
But if her friends get the wrong idea again,
it'll just make her feel bad.
Tomo again?!
I thought that after we
started middle school,
Yeah!
Tomo would start to calm down a little...
but she still shows no
signs of slowing down.
I can't play the games Tomo plays anymore.
She just keeps getting stronger,
and I don't want to just run around outside.
What can I do to be friends with her again?
Of course! I just need a girlfriend and—
Nah, that wouldn't be fair to the girl.
And it's not that easy to
get a girlfriend, anyway.
If only there was someone else between us...
Someone who could slow Tomo down a little,
who's cautious and has common sense.
On top of that, it'd have to
be a girl who could hang out
with me and Tomo while fully
understanding my situation.
Does lunch taste good when you eat alone?
Yeah. It just went from good to gross.
You always seem to be alone.
Why don't you try to make friends?
I'm alone because I can't make
friends even when I try.
That's a lie. You just don't want...
to replace Tomo.
If someone took her place,
you might never get back the relationship
you used to have with her.
That's your reasoning, isn't it?
I'm pretty tired of seeing
your sulky face by now.
Quit wallowing in self-pity,
and just make up with Tomo already.
I'm pretty sure she needs you, after all.
Gundo!
Gundo, would you...
maybe try going out with me?
That sounds like fun.
Hey... why did you agree to go out with me?
Because I figured it couldn't hurt.
Do you like me?
As if.
And I know it's not like
you love me, either.
Well, no...
I know I'm the one who asked,
but is this how "going out"
is supposed to work?
It's not a problem.
In the end, what matters most if you
want to keep up a good relationship
is whether or not it's in the
interest of both parties.
Huh? Your... Your hand?!
It's so soft!
I changed my mind. Can we stop now?
Your hand is all sweaty and gross.
Well, I'm this way, so see ya.
Hold it, Junichiro.
Something else you want?
Yes. I want you to call me by
my given name from now on.
Your given name?!
If I'm using your given name,
but you're not using mine,
will people believe we're going out?
Wouldn't they?
It'll just look like I have
a one-sided crush on you.
I can't deal with that.
I never thought Gundo would
actually become my girlfriend.
My girlfriend?
That's right... I have a girlfriend now.
And it's Gundo, the girl who argues
with me every time I see her.
She's... my girlfriend?
Sheesh... This sure has taken a weird turn.
I know this is a relationship
far removed from love and romance,
with no future at all...
But I still feel just a bit...
The good feelings ended there, though.
Our first date was a bike
ride up a mountain.
Well?! Awesome view, right?!
View?
Are you a total moron?
The second day, we went
fishing at the river.
Put this on your hook.
Ew! Keep that away from me!
Ew! It's alive!
Hey, Misuzu...
Was today not much fun for you?
Bingo.
I see...
If I tried to spend time
with Tomo right now,
I'd get exactly what I got from
these two days with Junichiro.
There's just no hope for me.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
I thought you might be able
to do something about this...
But the way you are now, you're just
kicking her into higher gear.
Hey, what's wrong, Misuzu?
You seem really down.
Did something happen?
Yes. A lot happened.
I'm sorry. I...
might not be able to keep being your friend.
Come on.
Ow! Hey!
Where are we going?
First period's about to start!
I don't care. Come with me.
What are you sulking about?
What do you mean, you can't
keep being my friend?
I'll knock you out!
That's extortion.
I mean, I have no physical strength at all,
so I can't play sports with you or anything.
What does that matter?!
It's not like I'm running
around every single day!
Goofing around with the guys is fun,
but the time I spend just being next
to you is way more precious to me.
Are you saying you don't feel the same?
Where do you learn things like that?
What? Did I say something weird?
Why would it matter that much
whether you're athletic or not?
I mean, like...
Oh, yeah!
Wouldn't it be cool for an athlete and
some kind of doctor to be friends?
What's "some kind of doctor"
supposed to mean?
Don't laugh!
All the things I was thinking
seem so silly now.
I guess going out with you
wasn't a total waste of time.
So I'll at least...
dump you soundly and completely.
Sorry, Misuzu.
Huh?
I know this sounds weird when I'm
the one who asked you out, but...
I feel like maybe we're not
a good match after all.
So let's just give up on going out, okay?
He... beat me to it!
Did you hear me? Hey, Misu—
Never... call me "Misuzu" again.
O-Okay.
I guess I'll have to handle this on my own.
I'm scared to find out how she'll react
when I talk to her after all this time,
but I'm prepared.
H-Hey, Tomo.
I wanted to talk to you about something.
I know I should be the one to talk first.
But what do I...
Hey. Hey, Jun.
Can I just tell her how I really feel?
But if I tell her that...
I just said your name.
Answer me, damn it!
Where did that come f—
Why did you just come up and
talk to me out of the blue?
After you avoided me all this time...
For a whole year...
I-I'm sorry!
It was my fault! Please don't cry!
Huh?
I'm not crying, you dumbass!
Why the hell were you avoiding
me all this time? Huh?!
When the school year first started,
people thought you and
I were... well... going out.
So I thought being around me would
just make things harder for you.
You were worried about
something that stupid?!
Huh?
If you and I both wanna be
together like we've always been,
who the hell cares what anyone else thinks?!
Well? What do you wanna do?
I want...
to be with you. Just like we always have...
I wanna be like that forever!
S-So just be with me, then!
As f-friends!
Yeah! You and I are best buds forever!
So let's have a lot more
good times together,
Tomo!
I thought we'd never change.
I thought it'd be best if we never changed.
But then I changed.
I think she has, too.
So I have to think of a way
I can still be with her forever.
First of all, I have to face her head-on.
What's the hold-up, Jun?
C'mon, we gotta get to school!
Face who Tomo is now head-on...
Head-on...
I had a vague hunch it might be true,
but isn't she actually...
really cute?!
(This behavior is suspicious)
Hey, you know, I'm all mixed up
It's too complicated, I'm freaking out
I can't figure out how to
say it, or how to read you
(crazy, crazy, drive me crazy, and that's...)
All this vagueness is just
pathetic and depressing
Antsy...
Impatient love
The truth is I love you,
but I keep beating around the bush
We're both the awkward type that'll try to
brush it off as a joke (so much pressure)
Sigh... Getting this exhausted
over nothing is so stupid
We'll never move forward or get
any answers that way, right?
Now you're suddenly grumpy, why all the
swirling emotions? I sense rain coming
Smoosh
You can have my umbrella,
just don't cry or get all mad and soaked
Ah, my broken heart and
broken body are at odds
I guess I can't deal with this
unless I put armor on, can I?
Constantly losing and being bewitched,
all at your mercy, is just frustrating
I'm gonna solve the riddle of
this impatient, shattering love
(Grinding, throbbing)
Ugh, I might be a bit
tangled in my own web now
But once I find my courage,
you'll see pure lo-love